Hi everyone. Welcome to the project work through for investigate a dataset.
你好 欢迎来到这个项目
I'll be doing the project with you today,
我会先做个示范
and you can see my process.
你可以先看看我是怎么做的
This project seems to be more open-ended,
项目是开放性的
where you choose a dataset, and you analyze it.
你需要选择一个数据集 然后进行分析
It looks like you'll need to install pandas, NumPy, and matplotlib.
我们需要安装 pandas、NumPy 以及 matplotlib
You probably don't need to install CSV, though,
如果你使用 pands 来读取 CSV 文件
if you could use read CSV from pandas.
你就不需要安装 CSV 了
Hopefully, you install these using Anaconda in the previous lessons.
希望你已经通过前面的课程安装了 Anaconda
So, the first step is to choose your dataset,
好的 第一步：选择数据集
and you can use this link to read about the different dataset options you have,
这个链接里提供了你可以选择的一些数据集
and some questions you can ask for your analysis.
以及你可以选择的探索方向
Today I'll be working through the Titanic dataset which
我要用的是 Titanic 数据集
is not an option for this project here.
这个数据集不是项目的可选数据集
But I'll be going through the same process and following the same guidelines.
我会运用前面课程里的所学的知识和技能 注意观看
The final deliverable for this project is a report and Python code for your analysis.
项目最终的交付成果是一份报告以及 用于分析的 Python 代码
If you're using a Jupyter notebook,
如果你在 Jupyter notebook 里做任务
you can include these two in the same file as long as you use like mark
你可以将报告和 Python 代码融合在一起
down cells and comments and stuff like that
你可以使用 markdown 单元格来注释
to clearly communicate your findings and process.
这样可以清晰地表达你的过程和最终洞察
Also you can ignore these tabs here,
你可以忽略这些标签
this are tabs that you probably won't see from your end.
在学员端是看不到这些标签的
This is the template that you'll use or can use for this project.
这是可用于这个项目的模板
It's also available to download just by pressing
如果你想在本地做任务
file download as I've had in the iPython notebook if you prefer to do it locally.
你可以这样下载下来
You could also get it over here.
这里也提供了下载链接
So, in your final project,
在这个项目里
you should have a note specifying what data set you analyzed,
你必须说明你用了哪个数据集
a statement of the questions you posed,
你要探寻的问题都是什么
a description of what you did to investigate those questions,
你为了找到问题的答案都做了些什么
documentation of any data wrangling you did,
对你的数据清洗过程的记录
and summary statistics and plots to communicate your final result.
用来传达最终洞察的数据和图表
This should be in a PDF or html file,
必须是 PDF 或者 html 格式
but if you do use iPython notebook you can
如果你使用的是 iPython notebook
just download it as a a html file from Jupyter notebooks.
你可以用 Jupyter notebook 下载 另存为 html 格式
I already downloaded the dataset,
我已经提前下载好了数据集
so I'll just go to this notebook,
来到 notebook
and I'm going to upload the dataset that I had.
上传数据集
Also you can just do this locally if you prefer that.
如果你想本地操作 也是可以的
Either way you will just be downloading it as html file like this,
不管是本地还是在线
whether it's here or locally and then submitting this file.
最终都是要下载成 html 格式 然后上传提交
So, let's take a look at this notebook.
好了 现在来看一下
Throughout the notebook, there are little tips here that will tell
notebook 里会有一些提示
you some advice on how to organize your report,
告诉你怎么能更好地组织你的报告
as well some advice on your analysis.
也会对你的分析提供一些建议
Here I'm going to replace the name with something more specific to mine, so my projects.
我要换个名字 与我的项目更相关一些
So, Titanic data analysis,
比如 Titanic Data Analysis
and I'll keep the table of contents because that is cool.
目录看起来蛮好的 我要保留
Here you just provide a brief introduction to dataset,
在这里 提供关于数据集和你的项目的
and your project I guess.
一些描述
So, I would say something like,
比如
in this project we'll be analyzing data associated with
在这个项目里 我将分析
the tragic event of the sinking Titanic.
关于泰坦尼克号沉没的一些数据
In particular, we'll be interested in finding trends among the passengers who survived,
我们将主要分析幸存乘客的特征以及
and how they differed from the passengers who did not survive.
他们与死难者群体的区别
To start, we'll import the packages we need for this analysis.
好的 先来导入这些常用库
So, NumPy, pandas matplotlib,
NumPy、pandas、matplotlib
and seaborne because not necessary but makes
Seaborne 不是必须的
visualizations look nice and matplotlib in line,
但是它可以帮助我们做出很漂亮的可视化
to make sure that those visualizations pop up in Jupyter notebooks.
还有 matplotlib inline 这样可视化就能在 Jupyter Notebook 里凸显出
The next section is data wrangling.
下一部分是数据清洗
This is just where you inspect your data to understand its structure,
目的是检视我们的数据、深入了解数据结构
and figure out any changes we have to make.
以及是否需要对数据进行某些改变
Here's where you actually make the changes to clean them.
这里可以记下你的数据清洗操作
So, let's first look at our dataset.
先来看一眼我们的数据集
I need to read in the dataset.
仔细看看
So, there's the passenger ID.
有乘客 ID
Each row is a passenger.
每一行是一名乘客
This is just a unique identifier,
这里用 0 和 1 来标记出该乘客是否遇难
whether they survived or not in ones and zeros.
或者幸存
The clustering their name, gender, age,
其他信息包括姓名、性别、年龄、
the number of siblings and spouses they have,
兄弟姐妹与配偶个数（SibSp）、父母与子女个数（Parch）、
number of parents and children they have, the ticket,
船费（Fare）、舱位（Cabin）、
fare, cabin and in embarks.
上船地点（Embarked）
This is just what they paid,
船费是船票的价格
and where they embarked from,
上船地点就是在哪里上的船
there's three C, S and Q according to Kaggle dogs,
一共有三个地点：C、S、Q
and in your report you should probably include description of their columns,
在报告里 建议对这些列名做出一些解释
and remember just over here it says,
另外 这里说了 你可以对单元格进行操作
use a lot of cells like you can press B to keep creating new cells or X to delete them,
比如 按键 B 来创建单元格 或者 按键 X 来删除单元格
and if you want to turn them to mark-down just press
如果要转为 markdown 文本 按键 M
M. If you're wondering why you can't use these,
你在编辑的时候 有可能无法使用这些快捷键
like while you're editing, it's because you're editing.
所以先退出编辑的单元格
So, you need to escape and then use those shortcuts.
然后应该就可以了
The next thing I'm going to do is,
接下来 从整体看下数据集情况
look at the shape.
所以
So, there are 891 passengers and 12 columns.
一共有 891 位乘客 以及 12 列信息
Here are some summary statistics.
这里是一些统计数据
Again, we're just trying to understand our data a little bit more,
记住 这一步的目的是进一步了解数据集
and also identify any changes will have to make.
然后再决定是否需要作出某种改变
Although, this data does look really clean.
目前看来 数据集整洁度很好
We probably won't be analyzing the passenger ID or
可能不需要乘客 ID 或者姓名
the name for our analysis because those are very specific to the passenger.
因为这是属于每个乘客的个人信息
Ticket and cabin I don't suspect to be super
船票和舱位 我觉得可能对我想要做的幸存者分析
useful in finding trends between survival as well.
也意义不大
Again, these are all things you can change.
如何整理信息将取决于你
It's all up to you. You should just make sure,
但是你需要保证
and the decisions you make are explained and elaborated on,
对你做出的数据整理做出一定的解释
in mark-down cells or comments.
可以在 markdown 文本单元格里或者进行注释
Just to let the reader know what you're doing.
以便读者能跟上你的思路
So, just from these summary statistics,
从这些统计数据来看
I can see that there are 38 percent of the passengers survived,
可以看到有 38% 的乘客存活了下来
there are three classes; one, two, and three,
有三个等级：1、2、3
and over 50 percent or at least 50 percent of them are in third class,
幸存者超一半的人都来自三等舱
which I assume is the cheapest and lowest class.
三等舱应该是最便宜、位置最底层的
There are very young babies and also an 18-year-old in this ship.
乘客年龄从宝宝到 80 岁老人都有
But the majority of them are between 20 and 40 years old.
但绝大多数是在 20 - 40 岁之间
Most of them came without siblings or spouses,
大多数人没有兄弟姐妹或者配偶
and without parents and children.
也没有父母和子女
Although, some can have as much as eight or six.
当然 有些数值则高达 6 或者 8
The fares are generally between 730,
船票在 7 / 8 - 30 之间
830, although, someone did pay 512.
当然也有付了 512 的
I am assuming that is first-class,
应该是一等舱的价格
and this is third- class.
这个显然是三等舱
We can check that later. But I'm assuming this is correlated with that.
我们可以稍后再验证 但是应该没错
Also, you can probably see here that the age has some missing values.
年龄有一些缺失值
So, the age has some missing values,
同样的
as well as the cabin and embarked.
舱位和上船地点也有缺失值
Although, we probably won't be analyzing cabin.
虽然 我们可能不会分析舱位
So, the first thing I'm going to do before I drop stuff,
好的 在删除某些缺失值的列或者未缺失值添加值之前
drop specific rows with no values or fill in
我要做的第一件事情就是
no values is drop the columns I'm not going to use.
把我不需要用的列删掉
So, I'm going to go ahead and drop the passenger ID,
包括乘客 ID
name, ticket, and cabin.
姓名、票号、舱位
Also if you're cleaning this data,
作为数据清洗的一部分
you could also change everything to lowercase if you want.
你也可以统一将所有字母改为小写字幕
Sometimes I do that just to be consistent because I
这样便于统一
don't like remembering what's lowercase and uppercase.
我不喜欢记哪些是大写 哪些是小写
Axis equals one to tell the function that we're using the column names or the columns,
Axis = 1 是说我们将会基于列名
and in places true so that we keep those changes.
inplace=true 是说我们保留这些更改
Now, we have the survived, class, gender,
好的 现在的列都有：是否幸存、等级、性别
age, family, staff, fare, and embarked.
年龄、家庭情况、船费、上船地点等
Now,what we have to do is fill in the age and the embarked.
现在要做的是填充年龄和上船地点的缺失值
I'll just handle them. For the age,
年龄有很多的缺失值
So, sometimes what I like to do is just look at what the rows look like.
我们可以先来看看这些行都长什么样
Because if they all have some certain characteristic,
是否有些共性
it will be like, good to know.
可以有助于我们的分析
Because there were sometimes I was like looking at projects
有时候你会发现
where all the null values are all from the same group or something.
所有的空值可能都属于某个类别
So, I just want to make sure I'm not missing anything.
所以我还是想看看保证自己没有错过任何重要信息
So I'll look at the data frame where the age is null and I look at a histogram of that.
先来看看年龄是空值的行 以及直方图
I didn't even look at the histogram of the whole data frame.
哦 对了 我还没有看过整个数据集的直方图呢
Okay. I'll do that first.
好吧 我得先看看整体情况
So, this is the entire data frame.
这是整体情况
This agrees with what we saw in the summary statistics.
和我们之前从统计数据里看到的差不多
The majority of them didn't pay too much,
大多数乘客票价很低
is very skewed to the right.
左边柱形很高
Most people are in the third-class.
大多数乘客是三等舱
More people didn't survive then survived.
遇难乘客多于幸存乘客
Also most people didn't come with parents,
大多数乘客没有跟兄弟姐妹、父母、子女
children, siblings, or spouses.
或者配偶一起乘船
Ages also skewed to the right with the majority being around 20 and 40.
年龄也非常聚集在 20-40 区间
I just did this because I wanted to check that these weren't super off from the general,
我们看年龄缺失行的直方图时
the rest of the data.
要看下是否有任何趋势和我们从整体数据集上观察到的趋势有很大的差异
The fare is also skewed to the right.
船票也是集中在左边柱形
Mostly, in the third-class.
猜测是三等舱
Although, most of the null I think is mostly,
也就是说 大多数年龄缺失记录的人
more people from these rows are in the third-class.
来自三等舱
Then survive more than survive,
幸存者少于遇难者
not that much family,
很少人有与家庭成员一起搭船
and the ages we obviously know.
还有年龄 当然是空值
So, I'm just going to fill in the null values with the mean.
我打算用均值代替空值
There are better ways to do this,
其实有其他办法
but this is pretty simple.
但这个比较简便
So, I will do that.
所以我就这么做了
I forgot to do in-place.
我忘了 inplace=true
Do not forget that.
你可别忘了
So, the ages were all filled with the means.
好了 填充好了
But the other one that we need to fill which was
另外一个有缺失值的列是上船地点
embarked the knot because this is not numeric data,
这不是数值 只是字母组成
doesn't have a mean is just letters.
因此无法用均值填充
But it looks like there's only two missing,
但目前看下来只有两行缺失上船地点
and those appear to be, these two rows.
应该是这两行
So, I think it'll be okay if we just drop them. So, yeah.
所以我们直接删除这两行 问题不大
Now we have a total of 889 rows instead of 891.
好的 现在我们一共有 889 行 而不是 891
So, I think that's all I needed to do for
除此之外 这个数据集还是很整洁的
the cleaning because otherwise this dataset is pretty clean.
所以我们的数据整理目前就是这些
So the next step is, Exploratory Data Analysis.
下一步——探索性数据分析
Also I'm just using this template right now to see what we have to do,
我会用到这个模板 这个模板对于我们开展下一步非常有帮助
because either way these little header should be
这些标题应该要替换成
more specific section names for your analysis.
更贴合你的项目主题的标题文字
But, there are useful tips and notes here.
会有一些非常有帮助的提示和注释
Just make sure analysis directed by questions.
在做任务的时候 一定要注意你的分析是围绕着你的问题展开的
So, survived is my dependent variable and these are my independent variables.
对于我的分析来说 幸存标记（Survived）是我的因变量 这些都是自变量
I'll just be exploring those associations among them.
我要做的就是分析它们之间的关系
So, I guess the first question I'll ask is whether the fare is associated with survival?
所以 我要提出的第一个问题是 船票是否与幸存有关？
Because I expect the expensive,
在这里 我的假设是船票越贵
people with high classes and expensive fares I
代表着乘客的舱位等级越高
think may have a higher chance of surviving.
也许会有着更高的生存几率
So, to make it easier to grab these rows easily in the future as well,
为了后续方便提取这些相关行
I'm going to create masks for
对于幸存的乘客行和遇难的乘客行
rows where the passenger survived and rows where they did not.
我会这样来做个区分（survived; died）
So, if I want to see all the fare is I could do something like,
我现在来看看所有幸存者的船票价格信息
fares of all the people who survived.
可以这么做
I could just do something like this which makes it a lot easier.
这样就很简单
So, let's look at the mean of that,
我们来看看幸存者船票价格的均值
as well as for the people who did not survive.
以及遇难者船票价格的均值
It does look like the people who survived had a much higher well,
似乎幸存者的船票价格确实会更贵些
a significant amount higher than the people who did not.
贵了一倍多
But we can see this more clearly if we look at the distribution
如果要更清晰地看看这个趋势
of fares and compare them in a visual.
我们可以看看两个人群分别的船票价格分布
So, let's do that.
然后通过图表来比较
You actually need a semicolon the last one to make sure the output doesn't pop up.
需要在最后一行用分号（；）结束 这样 output 就不会显示出来了
I'm also going to include a label in each one to make it
我还要加上标签 这样能更清楚地知道哪个颜色对应哪个人群
clear what each one is and make it a bit more transparent,
同时 调高透明度
so we can see more clearly where they overlap.
更容易看到两个人群的重合处在哪里
So, yeah definitely does look like the people who survived
这样就很明显了
had generally higher fares than the people who did not.
幸存者的船票价格普遍会比遇难者的船票价格要高
Especially with the lower class much more people died than survived.
尤其是低等舱的乘客中 遇难者多于幸存者
You'd set the bin number of bins or
你可以通过设置 bin 的数值来
columns to make it more generalized or not generalized.
让趋势变得更加突出或者更加“柔和”
So, if we use like 20 for example,
比如 我们设置为 20
we could see even more specific information of bins.
可以看到关于 bin 的更多详细信息
But fare also seems like it would be very closely correlated with class.
船票价格看起来跟等级息息相关
So, let's take a look at that as well.
我们来验证一下
So, if we grouped by the class and then we look at the Survived column,
如果我们来看下每个等级里幸存者的比例
it does definitely look like the higher the class,
好像真的是等级越高
the more likely you are to survive.
幸存概率越高
If you want to use a visual foreign analysis,
也可以进行可视化分析
we could just plot this in
绘制一个柱状图
a bar chart and again use semicolon if you don't want that output.
如果不想看到 output 需要在最后用分号（；）结束
Yeah, there definitely seems to be a correlation here.
关系非常明显
Similarly, I want to compare the distribution of
现在我还想比较幸存乘客与遇难乘客的年龄
So, I'll just copy and paste this and replace
因为变量非常非常相似 我可以拷贝这段代码
this with age because it's a very similar, very similar.
然后把变量替换为年龄
So, based on this plot,
根据这个图表
it does look like the really young children
年龄非常小的小孩会比其他年龄段的人
have a higher chance of surviving than other ages,
的幸存率更高
but other than that it doesn't look like they're too correlated.
但除此之外 我观察不到任何其他明显的关联
Next we can also look at the gender.
接下来看看性别这个变量
Also remember to be very descriptive and
记住 如果你是跟我一样在　Ｊｕｐｙｔｅｒ　Ｎｏｔｅｂｏｏｋ　里做任务
detailed in markdown cells to describe your analysis,
要在　ｍａｒｋｄｏｗｎ　单元格里
if you're doing this in Jupyter notebook.
对你的分析进行详细的记录和解释
So, if we want to look at the gender,
同样地　如果探索性别这个变量
we can also group by again,
我们可以根据性别来划分这些行
group by sex and then look at
然后看看幸存者的比例
the survived column and you can also plot this in a bar chart.
同样也可以用柱状图
It does look like females are
看上去女性比例确实比男性要高很多
definitely there are definitely more female surviving than men but just to make
但是为了排除一些其他因素干扰
sure I want to see if this isn't for
例如可能正好女性数量就特别少
some other weird reason like there are
然后她们还全部都是一等舱的
very few females and they just happened to meet first-class or something.
类似这样的神奇的情况
So, first I want to just check,
所以我需要确认下男性数量
there are definitely more males than females.
确实比女性多
If we do, lets say this.
然后进行这个操作
If we group by gender and we look at their classes,
根据性别　进行各个等级的数量统计
maybe a clear way to see this is the fare.
也可以通过船票价格来验证
So, we can do something like,
比如这样
we can look at the median fares for each gender and it
看看每个性别的船票价格的中位数
does look like the women are in more expensive,
女性的确实要高很多
are spending more, probably more in first class but let's see this visually.
可能是来自一等舱　我们可以再通过可视化来确认下
So, ideally you'd be using Matplotlib and making like a nice looking double histogram,
理想情况下　你应该是使用　Ｍａｔｐｌｏｔｌｉｂ　来创建经过修饰的直方图
but I'm trying to show you really quickly my analysis.
但我现在只是想快速地给你展示下我的分析结果
But even if you separate them by class,
可以看到　即使按照等级分
it is very clear that the women are surviving more than men.
女性幸存数量也比男性高
So, there does seem to be a pretty strong association between gender and survival.
所以很确定的是性别与幸存率有关
Another thing we can analyse is how having family on board is associated with survival,
我们也可以探索是否与家人同行影响了幸存率
and we can analyse this using the columns for siblings and spouses,
相关的列是兄弟姐妹配偶列（ＳｉｂＳｐ） 以及父母子女列（Ｐａｒｃｈ）
I'm imagining another double bar chart but I'm going to try doing
我会继续用　ｐａｎｄａｓ　来绘制图形
something a little bit better than this but still using pandas.
但会比这个稍微好看些
So, I'm going to use the analyser siblings and spouses column first
先分析兄弟姐妹配偶这一列
and use this mask again to see those that
用标记提取幸存者的行
survived and get the value counts because we're plotting a bar chart.
得出计数　因为我们绘制的是柱状图
I'm going to do the same thing with those who did not survive and
重复以上操作　只是换成了遇难者的行
these are just basically going to be on top of each other with different colours.
所以等下看到的柱形应该会是重合的　只是颜色不同
Ideally, also you'd be using Matplotlib but I'm just doing
理想情况下　你应该使用　Ｍａｔｐｌｏｔｌｉｂ
this really quickly to show you guys my analysis first.
但我在这里主要是想快速地给你示范我的分析
So, you can see that we need to be clear it labels.
哎呀　忘了标签
So, I'm going to insert a label here so we know which colour's which.
添加标签后就能看出颜色对应的是什么了
I'm going to semicolon to get rid of this output.
使用分号来隐藏　ｏｕｔｐｕｔ
So, a lot of people who have lots of families don't appear to be surviving.
这样看起来　与很多家庭成员同行的乘客的幸存概率比较低
People who have one survived more by
有一个兄弟＼姐妹＼配偶的乘客比其他人群的幸存概率会稍微高一些
a little bit and then majority of people were alone did not survive,
独自出行的大部分乘客都没有幸存
probably also imagine most of the population is probably in this category,
大多数乘客都符合独自出行的特征
so and most people did not survive.
也就是说　大多数人都没有幸存下来
We can do the same thing with the parents and children column and we see
对于父母子女一列的分析也是一样的
a similar trend here where the people with big families don't appear to
趋势也是类似的　父母子女一列的值比较高的或者独自出行的乘客
survive as well as those who are alone.
他们的幸存率较低
Maybe these are correlated with the first class or second class.
也有可能这部分人是一等舱或者二等舱
These are all things that can be explored
这些都值得深入探索
more and lastly the other column we can explore is,
最后我们要探索的是上船地点
how were they impact from where two is associated with survival.
是否与幸存率有关
We can do a similar thing with this too.
过程和之前类似
Also when you submit your report this should all be labeled.
记住你提交报告时　标签必须完整
So, to have a title, the axis labels,
需要有标题　横竖轴标签　图例
legend is good and like appropriate better tick labels
任何额外的类别标签
in this and just using Matplotlib for.
推荐使用　Matplotlib
So, the people in the S category seemed to be not having as much luck,
看起来从　Ｓ　上船的人群幸存率较低
C a bit better,
C 类稍微好点
Q is also not that great.
Q 也不怎么好
So, embark does that seem to have some association with it.
所以　上船地点貌似也与幸存率有点关系
So, this was just a really quick run-through of
好了　这就是探索变量间关系的一些示范
independent and dependent variables are going to rubic.
比如因变量和自变量
It looks like you only need to have
从项目要求来看　你需要在分析中包括
at least three independent variables and one dependent in your analysis.
至少　３　个自变量和　１　个因变量
At the bottom over here,
在底部
you should quickly summarise your findings and discuss limitations in your analysis,
你可以快速地总结下你的发现　然后讨论下你的分析的局限性
like for example, when I filled in the null values for the ages,
比如　当我在分析年龄的因素的时候
I just used the mean and there could be a better way of doing that.
我只是用了均值来代替　而实际上应该会有更好的办法
You could take into account
比如　你可以考虑年龄为空的那些行里的其他值
the other values in those rows where the ages now and use regression or something
利用回归模型等
to make a more accurate prediction of
来做出更准确的判断
what that could be and just places where you could explore more things.
同时有可能探索更多有趣的数据关系
But yeah, just make sure you use,
最后　我的建议是组织好你的报告
you organise your report well,
使用标题
use headings, use markdown cells.
使用　ｍａｒｋｄｏｗｎ　文本
If you have a report, same thing and clean up
修饰图表
your visuals and just be very thorough with your descriptions.
仔细描述
So, in this video I narrated it a lot but in a report,
在视频里　我口述了很多
you should describe everything and write it down.
但实际上　在你的报告里　你应该仔细地描述下来
I hope this was helpful and good luck with your analysis. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
希望这对你有所帮助　祝你好运！ 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6